[
 {
   "question": "Likewise the spirit also helped our infirmities for we know not what we should pray fro as we ought: but the spirit it self market intercession for us with groaning which on not be uttered.",
   "option_a": "Our inabilities and what we can do as human",
   "option_b": "our physical sickness",
   "option_c": "a viral disease",
   "option_d": "whooping cough that affects the thing",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Infirmities mean what we can’t do by our own selves"
 },
 {
   "question": "Who is like unto thee,\n\nO Lord, among the gods?\n\nWho is like thee,\n\nglorious in holiness,\n\nfearful in praises, doing wonders?\n\n\nAfter which great occasion did the composer of the song above, sing the song?",
   "option_a": "After the Passover",
   "option_b": "after the crossing of the red sea",
   "option_c": "after the killing of the first child of the Egyptians",
   "option_d": "after the first plague",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Exodus 14 : 13 - 31"
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the name of the first lead of the river that parted in the Garden of Eden?",
   "option_a": "Bison",
   "option_b": "Gijon",
   "option_c": "Pison",
   "option_d": "Euphrates",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "Do not blaspheme that worthy name by which ye are called. What in that worthy name?",
   "option_a": "Christian",
   "option_b": "new creature",
   "option_c": "Jesus",
   "option_d": "friend",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Jesus name in the worthy name by which we are called"
 },
 {
   "question": "The cost of being a disciple of Jesus is that?",
   "option_a": "We have to be fighting the devil always",
   "option_b": "we don’t follow our will but the will of Jesus our mater",
   "option_c": "we won’t have a place to lay our heads like Jesus",
   "option_d": "the foxes will late us.",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Luke 9:57\n\nwe lose our will to follow the will of the lord Jesus. They in the cost of being a disciple"
 },
 {
   "question": "They have taken away my Lord, and I know not where they laid him, was the statement Mary Magdalene told Jesus at his sepulcher. This statement shows.",
   "option_a": "She alone owns Jesus",
   "option_b": "She had a very strong and deep fellowship and relationship with Jesus",
   "option_c": "She very selfish and has personal interest",
   "option_d": "She is the sister of Jesus",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference John 20:13\n\nmany Magdalene was selfish or had personal interest she was just appreciative of the good Jesus did for her, so she was come in to a close relationship with him that she calls him her own."
 },
 {
   "question": "Whose sudden death of brought a turnaround in the life of obed-edom the Gittite?",
   "option_a": "Uzzaiah",
   "option_b": "Goliath",
   "option_c": "Uzzah",
   "option_d": "Elisha",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference 1 chronicles 13:6-14.\n\nUzzah was one of those drive the cast carrying the ark of covenant."
 },
 {
   "question": "“For her sins hare reached in to heaven, and God hath remembered her indignities.” Who in the statement talking about?",
   "option_a": "Jezebel",
   "option_b": "Babylon",
   "option_c": "Nigeria",
   "option_d": "USA",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "And I heard a great voice out of heavens saying, Behold, the tabernacle of God is with men, and he will dwell with them, and they shall be his people and God himself shall be with them and be their God. Who heard the great voice behind him?",
   "option_a": "James",
   "option_b": "Jesus",
   "option_c": "John the beloved",
   "option_d": "The Jesus",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Revelation 21:3.\n\nJohn the beloved that whole the book of revelation was the one who heard the voice"
 },
 {
   "question": "How many altars did balaam ask balak to bind for him?",
   "option_a": "5",
   "option_b": "3",
   "option_c": "7",
   "option_d": "9",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Numbers 23 : 1"
 },
 {
   "question": "How many dukes are there from the lineage of Edom?",
   "option_a": "thirteen",
   "option_b": "nine",
   "option_c": "five",
   "option_d": "ten",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference 1 chronicles 1 :51-54.\n\nNine duke came out of the family of Edom"
 },
 {
   "question": "The book of Acts of the Apostles contains the following except one.",
   "option_a": "How the early church started",
   "option_b": "The story of Jesus birth",
   "option_c": "The thing the Holy Spirit helped the Apostle to do in their life time",
   "option_d": "The storied of those that left faith because of love for the thing of the meld",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "The story of Jesus birth is not found in the book of Acts"
 },
 {
   "question": "For God hath not appointed us to wrath but to _______ salvation through our lord Jesus Christ",
   "option_a": "Grab",
   "option_b": "obtain",
   "option_c": "jump at",
   "option_d": "eye",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "We are not another to grab jump at or eye the salvation of God but to obtain the salvation through lord"
 },
 {
   "question": "The book of Revelation was written by ______ on the _______.",
   "option_a": "john the Baptist island of Everest",
   "option_b": "john the beloved, island of piton",
   "option_c": "john the Baptist island of patrons",
   "option_d": "john the beloved, island of Patmos.",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "John the Baptist was beheaded, only John the beloved escaped many death and wrote the book of revelation on patmos island"
 },
 {
   "question": "“For I have no pleasure in the death of him that dieth, saith the lord God wherefore turn yourselves and live ye.” which prophet did God tell this statement?",
   "option_a": "Samuel",
   "option_b": "Ezekiel",
   "option_c": "Jeremiah",
   "option_d": "Daniel",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Ezekiel 18:32.\n\nEzekiel was the prophet God was telling his mind about the death of a sinner."
 },
 {
   "question": "The mustard seed, in the parable of Jesus is said to be the ______ seed but when sown and it grown it become the greatest tree.",
   "option_a": "Best",
   "option_b": "most production",
   "option_c": "least",
   "option_d": "latest hybrid",
   "answer": "C",
  "solution": "Bible reference Matthew 13:31-32\n\nmustard seed size was are to typify the amount or size of faith we need to achieve it has a very small size – least"
 },
 {
   "question": "Hanniah, Mishael and ______ were the 3 special friends of Daniel in the Bible.",
   "option_a": "Gedaliah",
   "option_b": "Azariah",
   "option_c": "Nataliah",
   "option_d": "Jonathan",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Daniel 1:6.\n\nAzariah was the name of the third friend of Daniel. It was his leered name before they changed his name to Abednego"
 },
 {
   "question": "Israel was defeated by a very small country because",
   "option_a": "It was their destiny",
   "option_b": "Ai had more weapons",
   "option_c": "someone stole an accursed thing",
   "option_d": "someone sold them secretly",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Joshua  7. 27.\n\nAchan stole an accursed item. Sin was the only thing that made Israel lose battles."
 },
 {
   "question": "“Behold, I come as a thief. Blessed is he that watcheth, and keepeth his garment, lest the walk naked and they see his shame:\n\nWhy did Jesus say he will come as a thief?",
   "option_a": "because he in a thief",
   "option_b": "the likened it to the way thriven come because no one knows when thieves come",
   "option_c": "he wants to play hide and seek",
   "option_d": "God instructed him to",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Revelations 8 - 9\n\nBecause no one know when thief come to steal"
 },
 {
   "question": "The first miracle of Jesus was?",
   "option_a": "Stilling the storm",
   "option_b": "reading the scripture",
   "option_c": "turning water to write",
   "option_d": "heading the woman with the issue of blood.",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference John 2:\n\n\nJohn the beloved disciple of Jesus record that, that was the first miracle of Jesus"
 },
 {
   "question": "Likewise, ye wives be in subjection to your own husbands, that if any obey not the word, they also without the word be won by the conversation of the wives. What do you understand by the statement without the word”",
   "option_a": "We should do evangelism by closing or mouth",
   "option_b": "that those who would not listen to our preaching may be won to God by our godly actions",
   "option_c": "that it in the dispensation of dropping the bible",
   "option_d": "that that in what is reigning now",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "With out word- mean – even when we do not preach any more to them our actions & behavior will preach to them"
 },
 {
   "question": "Which of there 3 sinners did God course first after the eating of the forbidden fruit ?",
   "option_a": "Ground",
   "option_b": "Adam",
   "option_c": "Serpent",
   "option_d": "Eve",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Geneses 3 : 14"
 },
 {
   "question": "Paul record in the book of cession that Christians are scared by ______ through______",
   "option_a": "Faith, grace",
   "option_b": "grace, faith",
   "option_c": "convention, believing",
   "option_d": "agreement, understating",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "We were shared by Grace through faith, not by faith through grace"
 },
 {
   "question": "If any man love not the lord, let him be Anathemas:- anathema in the above sentence means",
   "option_a": "Repent",
   "option_b": "cursed",
   "option_c": "imprisoned",
   "option_d": "stoned",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Anathema means someone cursed or dispised"
 },
 {
   "question": "Josiah was eight years old when he began to reign, and he reigned _______ in Jerusalem",
   "option_a": "25 yrs",
   "option_b": "31 yrs",
   "option_c": "40 yrs",
   "option_d": "15 yrs",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference 2 kings2:11.27.\n\nJosiah reigned for 31yrs"
 },
 {
   "question": "Which prophet is popular with this statement in the Bible “can two walk together, except they be agreed”?",
   "option_a": "Ahaz",
   "option_b": "Amos",
   "option_c": "Famous",
   "option_d": "Hosea",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "Maranatha means?",
   "option_a": "Mary and Martha",
   "option_b": "come, Lord Jesus",
   "option_c": "oh how l love your coming",
   "option_d": "it is well",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "_________ The Son of Jeme, of the tribe or Benjamin - Judah, replaced king Saul as king.",
   "option_a": "Eliab",
   "option_b": "Absalom",
   "option_c": "David",
   "option_d": "Shammah",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "Be it unto me according to thy words, this statement by Mary was a statement of",
   "option_a": "Doubt",
   "option_b": "Gest",
   "option_c": "Faith",
   "option_d": "do quick and go",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Luke 1 : 38\n\nThis was a statement of faith because humanly speaking what the angel said is not possible, and she expect God to do it for"
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the significance of Jesus giving thanks to God and blessing the fish and the bread’, wife which he fed the 5000?",
   "option_a": "He need to show off to the people",
   "option_b": "he show we’ll have more when we give thanks to God for what we have",
   "option_c": "to encourage the boy who brought the breed and the fish",
   "option_d": "he needs to buy time",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Giving thanks make God give us more. That was what Jesus was showing us. And we must give thank to God who give us everything"
 },
 {
   "question": "The first record of the fall of Jerusalem was recorded in the book of _______",
   "option_a": "1 chronicles 1:1-end",
   "option_b": "2 king 24:25:1-17",
   "option_c": "2 Samuel 7: 3, 8: 1 end",
   "option_d": "none of the above",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference 2 kings 24-1-25:1-17.\n\n\nIt was the time that Nebuchadnezzar was raised to take Jerusalem captive"
 },
 {
   "question": "Who ordered that Naboth be killed?",
   "option_a": "Ahab",
   "option_b": "David",
   "option_c": "Jezebel",
   "option_d": "Joab",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference 1 king 21:8-15.\n\n\nJezebel the wife of king Ahab was wicked women, and she used her power to send people to kill Naboth"
 },
 {
   "question": "Whose donkey spoke in the bible?",
   "option_a": "Balikis",
   "option_b": "Balak",
   "option_c": "Balaam",
   "option_d": "Moses",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Number 22:28"
 },
 {
   "question": "How many generations are there each between Abraham to David, David to the generation that was exiled to Babylon, and from the exiled generation to Jesus?",
   "option_a": "42",
   "option_b": "14",
   "option_c": "uncountable",
   "option_d": "12",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Bible reference Matthew 1:17.\n\n\nThere are 14 generations each in the lineage of Jesus."
 },
 {
   "question": "So the ship master came to him and said to him, “what meanest thou, O sleeper? Arise, call upon thy God, if so be that God will think upon us, that we perish not”. Who did the ship master say this to?",
   "option_a": "Jesus",
   "option_b": "Janus",
   "option_c": "Jonah",
   "option_d": "Judah",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Jonah 1:6.\n\n\nJanus and Judas were never in the ship, Jesus was not under any ship man, so Jonah was the one told to call upon his God"
 },
 {
   "question": "But we have this treasure in earthen vessel that the Excellency of the power may be of God, and not of ourselves: an earthen vessel in the sentence above represents what?",
   "option_a": "Our flyover vase",
   "option_b": "the temple in Jerusalem",
   "option_c": "our human body housing the spirit",
   "option_d": "our brain",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Earthen vessel in anything made from soil or sand. Minivan made from the soil so our are the earthen vessels"
 },
 {
   "question": "Peter in the book of Act was totally different from the peter in the four Gospels. What made the difference in him?",
   "option_a": "The presence of the other brethren in the upper room",
   "option_b": "The wine he drank in the early hours",
   "option_c": "The Holy Ghost in his life",
   "option_d": "He was just putting up bold face",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Act 1 : 8, Act 2 : 1 - 4, 13.\n\nthe holy ghost differentiate a Christian from a non-Christian. He enable us to do what we can’t do naturally."
 },
 {
   "question": "“Ye do err, not knowing the scripture, nor the power of God”. Jesus implies what with this statement?",
   "option_a": "Abusing the Pharisees became they are fool",
   "option_b": "that we make mistake and do not judge right scriptural thing because we do not know the scripture and what the power of god can do",
   "option_c": "he wants in to be filled with the Holy Ghost",
   "option_d": "We are like idiots",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Matthew 24:23-29\n\nknowledge of the scripture and the power of god frees us from error misjudgment"
 },
 {
   "question": "How old was Noah where the rain of the great flood started?",
   "option_a": "A youth of 30years",
   "option_b": "450years",
   "option_c": "600years",
   "option_d": "650years",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Bible reference Gen 7 : 11"
 },
 {
   "question": "Jesus compared or likened the faith we need to do the impossible to a mustard seed. Why did he use the mustard seed?",
   "option_a": "That was what he saw beside him",
   "option_b": "we only need a small spark of faith to do or achieve thing that seem too great to achieve",
   "option_c": "because faith was nit something sign",
   "option_d": "it was the best-selling seed then.",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "John 17:6\n\nA small faith in God can work mighty miracles"
 },
 {
   "question": "The miracles of James and peter and their preaching led to their arrest but ______ people believed God through them.",
   "option_a": "3000",
   "option_b": "5000",
   "option_c": "4000",
   "option_d": "millions",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Act 4:4\n\n5000 people were recorded to believe God thing the preaching of James a peter"
 },
 {
   "question": "The first miracle performed in the book of Act happened at the _______",
   "option_a": "The fish gale",
   "option_b": "the beautiful gate",
   "option_c": "at the gate of the temple called beautiful",
   "option_d": "at Solomon poet",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Act 3 : 1 - 11\n\nAt the gate of the Temple called beautiful. The Temple is called Beautiful"
 },
 {
   "question": "............ was the first man who has no record of beginning or end, or any record of his parents or his place of descent.",
   "option_a": "Enoch",
   "option_b": "Melchizedek",
   "option_c": "Adam",
   "option_d": "Abimelech",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 }
]